<images>
	
	
	<photo image="images/101.jpg" colorboxImage="images/101.jpg"  colorboxInfo="Item 01" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>Having lived in Bayside all but the first two years of her life, Marie Dwyer not only saw Bayside transform from a rural farming community into a thriving suburban town, she actively participated in its development and contributed to its economic growth.  Dwyer was a third-generation horticulturist as both her father and grandfather Eugene and Joseph Bechamps, were well-known nurserymen in Flushing.  While raising four children with her husband John J. in their home on Fifth Street (217th Street), Dwyer opened a florist shop on the northwest corner of Bell Boulevard and 39th Avenue (formerly Ashburton Avenue) in 1925.  Dwyer was an active member of the Bayside Woman's Club, the Bayside Yacht Club, and Sacred Heart Church.</body>]]></photo>	
	
	<photo image="images/102.jpg" colorboxImage="images/102.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 02" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">	
	<![CDATA[<body>Since 1996 Ann-Margaret Carrozza has represented District 26 in the New York State Assembly and is currently serving her seventh term as its Deputy Majority Whip. Carrozza, a mother of two children, is also a practicing attorney. She received her J.D. from Hofstra University where she served on the Law Review. Carrozza is an active member of the New York State Bar Association – Trusts and Estates and Elder Law sections, the Queens County Bar Association – Elderly and Disabled committee, the Association of the Bar of the City of New York – Surrogates Court Committee, and the National Academy of Elder Law Attorneys. She also serves as a member of the Legal Advisory Board of the Long Island Alzheimer’s Foundation.  </body>]]></photo>
	
	<photo image="images/103.jpg" colorboxImage="images/103.jpg"colorboxInfo="Item 03" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>After graduating from Bayside High School in 1970, Shulman-Baker went on to receive a BA in geology from SUNY Buffalo, a medical degree from Cornell University and a master’s degree in public health from the University of Texas. After completing her residency, Baker joined NASA as a medical officer and served as a physician in the Flight Medicine Clinic at the Johnson Space Center before becoming an astronaut in 1985. A veteran of three flights, Baker has logged over 686 hours in space. Her flights include the 1989 STS-34 Atlantis, which successfully deployed the Galileo to explore Jupiter; the STS-50 Columbia, which was the first flight of the US Microgravity Laboratory and the first Extended Duration Orbit flight; and the 1992 STS-71 Atlantis mission, the first Space Shuttle mission to dock with the Russian Space Station Mir. Baker has two daughters and currently lives with her husband, Kenneth J. Baker, in Texas, where she serves as the chief of the Astronaut Office Education/Medical Branch, Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center. </body>]]></photo>
	
	<photo image="images/104.jpg" colorboxImage="images/104.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 04" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	
	<![CDATA[<body>Carol Marian is the current president of Bayside Historical Society and has been a dedicated member since 1966. She raised her two children in Bayside where they attended Sacred Heart School. Marian has been a champion of the quality of life issues pertaining to zoning, parks, and preserving the community’s natural and historical legacy. Through the years, Marian has been the chairperson of the Bayside Beautification Committee, parks chairperson for Community Board 11, founder of the Sacred Heart Leisure Club, member of the Udall Cove Committee, and member of the Alley Restoration Committee, the precursor of Alley Pond Environmental Center. Marian’s leadership and boundless energy inspire and motivate Bayside Historical Society as the organization approaches its 50th anniversary. 
</body>]]></photo>
	
	<photo image="images/105.jpg" colorboxImage="images/105.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 05" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank"> 
	
	<![CDATA[<body>Betsy Pilling, licensed real estate broker and owner of Pilling Real Estate, Inc., has been associated with the family business for over 30 years. During the 1990s she managed the office and is now the broker/owner. She is a member of the Long Island Board of Realtors and the North Shore Multiple Listing Service. Pilling juggles the demands of an active real estate brokerage with the obligations of raising three school-age children. Over the years, she has found the time to devote to community organizations, such as Sacred Heart parish and the Bayside Business Association, and served as president of the Kiwanis Club of Bayside.
</body>]]></photo>
		
	<photo image="images/106.jpg" colorboxImage="images/106.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 06" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	
	<![CDATA[<body>Maria Calegari, a former principal ballerina, began her ballet career with lessons in Bayside at the age of three-and-a-half. In 1974, the 17-year-old Calegari was personally recruited by George Balanchine to join the New York City Ballet. She was promoted to principal dancer in 1983 and performed at that level for 10 years. Since 1994, Calegari has taught students and professional dancers in New York and Connecticut and has staged dance productions throughout the world. Calegari’s latest dance endeavor is the establishment of a quality dance program in her Putnam County community.</body>]]></photo>
	
	<photo image="images/107.jpg" colorboxImage="images/107.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 07" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">	
	<![CDATA[<body>Originally from Charleston, South Carolina, Lawrence stood apart from her Bayside contemporaries as the southern-born wife of Colonel Frederick Newbold Lawrence(1834-1916). She had three daughters with Lawrence and also raised a step-daughter from her first marriage.  Lawrence was a grand hostess as well as a philanthropist and was instrumental in establishing All Saints Episcopal Church on Montauck Avenue and Second Street (40th Avenue and 215th Street), donating the property for the site of the church in 1891. Three years later Lawrence died on pneumonia at the age of 59 and was buried in the Lawrence Family Cemetery (216th Street and 42nd Avenue).</body>]]></photo>
	
	
	<photo image="images/108.jpg" colorboxImage="images/108.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 08" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	
	<![CDATA[<body>Loretta Young Napier is a fifth generation Baysider who attended both PS 130 and Bayside High School. She married her high school sweetheart, Raymond Napier, and together they raised three children in Bayside where she was an executive member of Community Board 11. Young Napier was a social worker and psychologist in the New York State Criminal Justice System before she retired in 1991. Her activism is driven by social justice issues. She has been awarded citations from the Queens Borough President’s Office, Northeast Queens and Nassau County NAACP, and former New York State Governor Mario Cuomo for her efforts. Today, Young Napier resides in Hempstead, NY and is actively involved with the Union Baptist Church where she is a member of both the Women’s and the Social Justice Ministries.
	</body>]]></photo>
	
	
	<photo image="images/109.jpg" colorboxImage="images/109.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 09" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>Claire Shulman, the first woman elected as Queens Borough President, began her professional career as a registered nurse. While raising her family of three children, she was involved in many charitable and civic organizations which led to her successful political career. She served as Queens Borough President from 1986 until 2001. Her major accomplishments included: the economic revitalization of downtown Jamaica; expansion of the borough's economic base; capital construction programs to improve the borough's infrastructure; increased funding for senior citizen centers, cultural programs and libraries; and securing funding for 35,000 additional school seats in the Board of Education’s five-year Capital Plan. Since leaving public office, Shulman has continued to be active in public and civic affairs, serving as a board member of the Queens County Savings Bank, Flushing Cemetery, St. Mary’s Hospital for Children, New York Hospital Queens and the Primary Care Development Corporation.</body>]]></photo>
	
	<photo image="images/110.jpg" colorboxImage="images/110.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 10" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">	
	<![CDATA[<body>Victoria Schneps-Yunis is the publisher of The Queens Courier and CEO of its parent company, Schneps Publications, Inc. Schneps-Yunis started The Queens Courier in her basement in 1985, and has expanded its circulation to 154,000, with offices on Bell Boulevard, Bayside. The weekly newspaper informs the people of Queens about social, political, business, athletic, and school news. Schneps Publications, Inc. publishes The Queens Courier as well as 10 other publications. Schneps-Yunis founded the Working Organization for Retarded Children and Adults, a not-for-profit agency operating group homes for developmentally disabled children and adults.  She sponsors the annual Top Ten Women in Business Networking Awards Dinner, raises money for charitable causes, such as the Fund for Public Schools, and serves on the board of directors of the Queens Museum of Art.
</body>]]></photo>
	
	<photo image="images/111.jpg" colorboxImage="images/111.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 11" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>Known as the First Lady of Bayside, Wettingfeld moved to the area with her parents Anne Nemec and Joseph H. Brown when she was nine years old. She attended PS 31, Bayside High School, and Barnard College. She also earned a master’s degree in political science from Columbia University and later became a freelance contributor to Columbia University Press. She married fellow Baysider Henry Wettingfeld and raised a son and daughter in the home that she still resides in today. For more than a decade, Wettingfeld has been a contributor to the Bayside Times with her regularly featured column “Our History.” As the daughter of Joseph H. Brown, the founder of the Bayside Historical Society, Wettingfeld has honored her father’s legacy by continuing her support as a trustee of BHS.
	</body>]]></photo>
	
	<photo image="images/112.jpg" colorboxImage="images/112.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 12" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>Judith Limpert began her career in banking over 25 years ago as a part-time teller. Today she is vice president and branch manager of Alma Bank in Bayside. Immersed in the Bayside community, Limpert is currently the president of the Bayside Business Association, which she founded shortly after her involvement with the installation of holiday lights on Bell Boulevard.  She is also a trustee and former vice president of Bayside Historical Society as well as a former vice president of the Kiwanis Club of Bayside. Limpert is involved with many annual fundraising events for the community including “A Taste of Bayside” and was instrumental in the formation of the Bayside Village Business Improvement District.  Limpert is actively involved with her alma mater, Queensborough Community College, and QCC’s Partners for Progress program. In 1997 QCC awarded her the Ella S. Streator Award for distinguished alumni.</body>]]></photo>
	
	<photo image="images/113.jpg" colorboxImage="images/113.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 13" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">	
	<![CDATA[<body>JoAnn Wagner, a lifelong Bayside resident, is a mother of six, an active member of Our Lady of the Blessed Sacrament Home School Association, and the coach of Saint Francis Prep Girls Varsity Basketball team. She and her children all attended OLBS School and Saint Francis Prep High School. Wagner played basketball as a student at SFP (formerly Bishop Reilly High School) and returned in 1974 to start the Junior Varsity Girls team. She has coached the SFP Junior Varsity and Varsity teams for over 30 years, and earned 17 Diocesan Championships, three City Championships, and three Coach of the Year Awards. In 1993, she was inducted into the Girls Catholic High School Athletic Association Hall of Fame, and in 2010, she was inducted into the Saint Francis Prep Hall of Fame. Photo courtesy Damion Reid
	</body>]]></photo>
	
	
	<photo image="images/114.jpg" colorboxImage="images/114.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 14" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>Faggs grew up in Bayside and honed her skills as a sprinter at the Police Athletic League in Flushing.  She was a graduate of Bayside High School and was awarded a scholarship to attend Tennessee State University. At 16, Faggs competed in the 1948 Summer Olympic Games held in London.  Four years later she and her teammates took home the gold for the 100-meter relay at the 1952 Summer Olympics in Helsinki.  In the 1956 Olympics held in Melbourne, she and her relay team received a bronze metal for that same event.  Faggs was the first American woman to compete in three Olympics and was elected to the U.S. Track and Field Hall of Fame in 1976.</body>]]></photo>
	
	
	<photo image="images/115.jpg" colorboxImage="images/115.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 15" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">	
	<![CDATA[<body>Lois Christie has taken her passion for hair styling and parlayed it into a thriving business that has grown exponentially over the last several decades. Christie began her career as a stylist, opening her own salon in Bayside on 46th Street and Bell Boulevard, where she honed her skills as both a hair dresser and businesswoman. She later moved to a second location on Bell Boulevard near 35th Avenue before moving to the Bay Terrace Shopping Center. Today Christie & Co. Salon ● Spa boasts an 8,000-square-foot space with over 90 employees and provides services to more than 250 clients a day. Through the years, Christie has supported many organizations including the American Cancer Society, Working Organization for Retarded Children (WORC), and St. Mary’s Hospital for Children. On the local level, Christie has sponsored both school and athletic events in the Bayside area.
	</body>]]></photo>
	
	
	
	<photo image="images/116.jpg" colorboxImage="images/116.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 16" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>Born in Liverpool, England, Allison came to American when she was 17 from her home in Belfast, Ireland.  She married David Allison of Bayside in 1931.  They had two sons and in 1938, bought their home at 38-32 205th Street.  Allison began working for the Flushing-Bayside Times in its advertising department in 1947, and was promoted to Advertising Manager a year later.  In 1951 Allison purchased the Bayside Times and held it until her death in 1977.  Through her newspaper, Allison led many community campaigns, including increased police protection and saving the local firehouse from closing during the economic downturn of the 1970s.  She was instrumental in raising awareness for the restoration of the Alley, the Lawrence Family Cemetery, and the preservation of Fort Totten.</body>]]></photo>
	
	
	<photo image="images/117.jpg" colorboxImage="images/117.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 17" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">	
	<![CDATA[<body>Known as the Dowager Queens of American Stage and Screen, May Robson, took up acting to support her only child after her husband Edward Gore passed away in 1883 just shortly after their third year of marriage.  Robson and her son settled in Bayside on Wright Avenue (209th Street), and in 1889 she married a police surgeon, Dr. Augustus Brown. It was only after her second husband died in 1922, and her son grown, that she decided to relocate to California.  Leaving her son in charge of her Bayside home, Robson purchased a second home in Beverly Hills, making her possibly one of the first bi-coastal commuters.  While she had always acted, Robson's film career blossomed in her later years. Usually portraying grandmotherly types, she starred in over 60 films including the original Alice in Wonderland (1933), Lady for a Day (1933), in which she received a Best Actress Oscar nomination for her role as Apple Annie, and Bringing Up Baby (1938).</body>]]></photo>
	

<photo image="images/118.jpg" colorboxImage="images/118.jpg"  colorboxInfo="Item 18" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>Annie Lawrence Bell was born into one of Bayside's most prominent families and grew up with strict Quaker sensibilities.  At the then late age of 29, Bell married Frederick Storm, a business-man who served as a U.S. representative in the 57th Congress from 1901 to 1903.  Bell was instrumental in developing the Bayside community as she and her husband donated land and funds to both the Bayside Woman's Club and the public meeting house known as Literary Hall. After her husband died, Bell continued to serve as landlord for several of the homes she owned along First Street (214th Street), which was then known as Brides' Row in the Lawrence Manor neighborhood.  Even when she was well into her 80s, she could be seen going from house to house, collecting rent from her tenants at the beginning of each month.</body>]]></photo>


<photo image="images/119.jpg" colorboxImage="images/119.jpg"  colorboxInfo="Item 19" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>Not only did Margaret Purchase raise four children and manage her own realty business on Bell Boulevard, she was extremely active in the American Legion Auxiliary Post 510 for almost half a century. Located on 38th Avenue, the Post benefited from her tireless service as Purchase served as both its president and poppy chairman for many years. In her capacity as president, Purchase marched in annual parades, hosted monthly parties for disabled veterans at Northport Veterans Hospital, and was instrumental in raising funds for the war monument honoring Bayside soldiers who died during WWI. The obelisk stands at the corner of Northern Boulevard and the Clearview Expressway overpass.</body>]]></photo>
	
<photo image="images/120.jpg" colorboxImage="images/120.jpg"  colorboxInfo="Item 20" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>Environmental activist Virginia Dent co-founded Udalls Cove Preservation Committee in 1969 as a means to preserve the marshy wetlands area along Little Neck Bay.  Working together with friend and fellow preservationist Aurora Gareiss, the two accomplished their goal nearly 22 years after their fight began.  Perseverance finally paid off in 1990 when New York City purchased a 50-acre tract of land and dedicated it as a public park. Dent also served as the executive director of the NYS Northeastern Queens Nature and Historical Preserve Commission, as well as the president of the Bayside Historical Society.</body>]]></photo>	
	



	
	
	
	<photo image="images/121.jpg" colorboxImage="images/121.jpg" colorboxInfo="Item 21" colorboxClass="image" url = "http://www.flashxml.net" target="_blank">
	<![CDATA[<body>Geraldine Spinella’s ancestral roots in Bayside date back to 1890. She has lived here her entire life and her dedication to the community is evident in the many leadership roles she has assumed over the years. Spinella was part of the Restoration Advisory Board (RAB) to save Fort Totten and as a commissioner for the (now defunct) State of New York Northeastern Queens Nature and Historical Preserve Commission (SNEQ), strove to protect the historical and environmental integrity of the fort.  During her tenure as president (1996-2001) and executive director (2002-2008) of the Bayside Historical Society, she was instrumental in completing much of the interior restoration of the Officers’ Club.</body>]]></photo>
	


</images>











